Guide to the Arthur A. Cohen Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- October 2003 Acquisition, 1941-1987; 19.54; (18 boxes)
  - Der Jude, editorial correspondence, University of Alabama Press, 1978-1981 (Box 34)
  - The Natural and Supernatural Jew, Heer essay, 1964 (Box 34)
  - A People Apart, promotion, Cohen & Garvin, 1972 (Box 34)
  - Wolff, Helen, Helen & Kurt Wolff Books, Harcourt Brace Jovanovich, 1977-1978 (Box 34)
  - From Hannah Arendt to Erika Hertz, Confessions of a Romancier a Clef, 1983 (Box 34)
  - The Tremendum, publicity correspondence, 1981 (Box 34)
  - The Myth of the Judeo Christian Tradition, Schocken Paper, 1971 (Box 34)
  - The Myth of the Judeo Christian Tradition, correspondence, 1962-1971 (Box 34)
  - The Myth of the Judeo Christian Tradition, Harper & Row, 1970 (Box 34)
  - Pen-Klein Award, 1986 (Box 34)
  - The Myth of the Judeo Christian Tradition, 1963-1970 (Box 34)
  - Personal correspondence, 1955-1956 (Box 35)
  - Yom Kippur Sermon JTS, 1957, 1960 (Box 35)
  - Sermons, 1951-1953 (Box 35)
  - Jewish History, Salo Baron, Columbia, 1949 (Box 35)
  - Park Avenue Synagogue, Seminar: SK. Buber Brunner Barth, 1950 (Box 35)
  - Idea of God in Great System, Hartshorne, 1950 (Box 35)
  - Isaiah: Irwin Essay, On Book of Isaiah, Chicago, 1950 (Box 35)
  - History of Literary Criticism essay, Bosanq, Olson, Chicago, 1950 (Box 35)
  - Seminar on Martin Buber, Hillel Foundation, Chicago, 1950 (Box 35)
  - Seminar on Tisha B'Ab Heschel et al, 1953 (Box 35)
  - Yom Kippur Sermon, Notes on Immortality, 1955 (Box 35)
  - Exodus Project: Commentary on Parshah Jetro, 1956 (Box 35)
  - Sermon: Yom Kippur 5115, 1956 (Box 35)
  - Proposed outline of "Judaism for the Gentiles", undated (Box 35)
  - "Kant's Fourth Question," essay, 1958 September 3 (Box 35)
  - "Catholicism and a Liberal Fallacy," unpublished article, 1957-1958 (Box 35)
  - Institute for Religious & Social Studies, JTS, 1960 January 5 (Box 35)
  - "To Reason Together," commentary on Isaiah Project, 1962 (Box 35)
  - "Jewish Theology for the Interregnum," unpublished manuscript, 1962 (Box 35)
  - Press conference: Cohen & Karth Barth, 1962 May 1 (Box 35)
  - Berdyaev, Nicholas Reader, Doubleday Anchor, 1963-1971 (Box 35)
  - "Anti-Semitism," unpublished essay, 1963 (Box 35)
  - "Myth of Judeo-Christian Tradition," lecture, Vassar, 1965 (Box 35)
  - "Speaking of Books," New York Times, 1965 (Box 35)
  - Project: The Other Promised Land, 1966 (Box 35)
  - "Is Theology UnJewish," lecture, Park Avenue Synagogue, 1966 October 17 (Box 35)
  - "Reflections on Theological Method and the Task of Jewish Theology," lecture, Conference at Columbia University, original sent to Wayne State Press for Publication, 1967 November (Box 35)
  - "Reflections on Theological Method and the Task of Jewish Theology," lecture, Conference of Jewish Philosophy, Columbia, 1967 (Box 35)
  - "Jeptha's Vow", undated (Box 35)
  - "Judaism Despite Christianity," Rosenstock-Huessy and Franz Rosenzweig, 1969 (Box 35)
  - Lecture on Emotion in Notes, Bible, NYU, 1969 (Box 35)
  - "Failure, Biography & the Creative Act," lecture, ARC, 1970 February 14 (Box 35)
  - Dialogue, Weitzmann Institute, Rehovot, Israel, 1971 (Box 35)
  - Commencement, Cherry Lawn School, 1971 June (Box 35)
  - "Messianism and In the Days of Simon Stern," talk (not given), 1973 (Box 35)
  - "Politics and Jewish History," Temple Emmanuel, 1973 April 22 (Box 35)
  - "Jewish Theology and Jewish Existence," teaching, Brown University, 1973 (Box 35)
  - "Messiah Falso or Failed?," Stolnitz Memorial lecture, University of Indiana, 1974 April 1 (Box 35)
  - Acceptance of Edward Lewis Wallant Prize, 1974 March 17 (Box 35)
  - Grob, David, 1974 (Box 35)
  - "Tower of Babel and the Origins of Language," Cornell University, 1974 April 21 (Box 35)
  - "Imagining the Holocaust: Some Notes on Contemporary Fiction," B'nai B'rith Award, 1975 (Box 35)
  - Correspondence Q-R, undated (Box 35)
  - Bernstein Conference on Jewish Studies, University of Rochester, 1976 February (Box 35)
  - National Breira Conference, Washington DC, remarks, 1976 (Box 35)
  - Chicago lectures, 1976 November (Box 35)
  - Rosenzweig seminar HUC-JIR, 1977 (Box 35)
  - Archimedean Fulcrum, 1979-1980 (Box 35)
  - from notebooks, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1977 April 18 (Box 35)
  - Address, American Jewish Literature, The Jewish Student Press Service, 1977 November (Box 35)
  - Symposium: Spiritual Resistance Art from Concentration Camps, Jewish Museum, 1978 May 2 (Box 35)
  - Correspondence: Tisch Lectures Brown, Neusner, Dietrich et al., 1979 April (Box 35)
  - Tisch Lectures: The Matrix of Jewish Theology, Brown, 1979 April (Box 35)
  - "Albert Salomon as Intellectual Cicerone: A Memoir & Celebration", 1979 (Box 35)
  - Symposium: "Text and Its Interpretation," Stony Brook/Binghamtom, 1979 (Box 35)
  - Acts of Theft, advertisement, Coda Magazine, 1980 October (Box 35)
  - Symposium: Present Tense, 1981 (Box 35)
  - "Messiah According to the Jews," conference at Columbia University, 1981 April (Box 35)
  - Hamilton College, 1981 (Box 35)
  - Cooper Union Lecture, reading with Cynthia Ozick, 1981 (Box 35)
  - "Remarks by Arthur A. Cohen," Herbert Bayer Exhibition, Janus Gallery, 1983 October 1 (Box 35)
  - Opening remarks, Warsaw Ghetto, Exhibition: Oyneg Shabbes YIVO, 1983 (Box 35)
  - Present Tense: Tenth Birthday Address, 1983 May 11 (Box 35)
  - "Franz Rosenweig and the Crucifixition," lecture, American Academy of Religion, Dallas, 1983 (Box 35)
  - "A Few Remarks on American-Jewish Writing," PMLA, New York, 1983 December (Box 35)
  - Address to the Annual Meeting National Foundation for Jewish Culture, 1983 September 11 (Box 35)
  - Bayer, Herbert, History of Graphic Design, RIT, 1983 April (Box 35)
  - Art & Ardor (Ozick), unpublished, 1983 (Box 35)
  - "Theology and Fiction: Two Types of Imagination," lecture, Boston University, 1983 (Box 35)
  - "The Holocaust in My Life and Work," lecture, The Jewish Museum, 1983 April 7 (Box 35)
  - "Russian Futurism & Constructivism: An Overview" AIGA-NY, lecture, 1984 (Box 35)
  - Correspondence: Saul Friedlander Rev. "Reflections of Nazism," unpublished, 1984 (Box 35)
  - "The Intellectual in Jewish Literature," Temple Sinai, Washington DC, 1984 December 16 (Box 35)
  - Association of Jewish Studies, Boston, 1985 (Box 35)
  - Baron, Salo, 90th Birthday letter, 1985 (Box 35)
  - "The Archimedian Fulcrum," The History of a Metaphor, 1985 (Box 35)
  - Theological Materials and Notes, 1985 (Box 35)
  - PEN International Conference, "Utopian Imagination", 1986 January (Box 35)
  - Spertus College of Judaica, Honorary Degree, 1985 October 16 (Box 35)
  - Soloveitchik/Columbia, 1986 (Box 35)
  - Proffer, Carl Memorial & Ardis Papers, 1985 (Box 35)
  - Bar Mitzvah certificate, University of Chicago Master of Arts diploma, 1941, 1948 (Box 36)
  - Arthur A. Cohen, Chicago, 1950 (Box 36)
  - Work on Midrash Rabah: Genesis, undated (Box 36)
  - Systematic Theology: Tillich, Union, 1949 (Box 36)
  - "Dialectic in Hegel and Kierkegaard," Wahl: History of Existentialism, 1947 (Box 36)
  - Ethics of Non-Christian Religion, Wach, undated (Box 36)
  - Comparative Doctrine: Wach, Chicago, 1947 (Box 36)
  - Tillich, Paul, undated (Box 36)
  - "Jewish Mysticism," Mysticism East-West, Wach, undated (Box 36)
  - Form and Structure in the Novel: Brown, E.K., 1950 (Box 36)
  - "Evil-Freedom Satre-SK," Wahl: Phenomenology and Existence, 1948 (Box 36)
  - Primitive Religion: Wach, undated (Box 36)
  - Contemporary Metaphysics: Notes and Essay, Whitehead, undated (Box 36)
  - Essay on Spanish Civil War 1937, 1941 (Box 36)
  - Leibniz, undated (Box 36)
  - Aesthetics Metaphysics Novel, undated (Box 36)
  - John Locke, undated (Box 36)
  - Rene Descartes, undated (Box 36)
  - Seminar on Sefer Ha-Mada of Maimonides, Hillel, Chicago, 1950 (Box 36)
  - Theories of Sympathy: Salomon, New School, 1949 (Box 36)
  - McKeon essay on More Geometrico Spinoza's Ethics, Leo Hebraeus: Dialoghi D'Amore, undated (Box 36)
  - Palestinian Judaism: Marcus, essay: "The Idea of Minuth," Chicago, 1950 (Box 36)
  - Herberg, Will, 1952-1953 (Box 36)
  - General Theory of Culture, Riezler, 1946 (Box 36)
  - Dante: Borgese, undated (Box 36)
  - Aesthetics, Vivas, essay: Croce, undated (Box 36)
  - Aristotle: McKeon, Chicago, 1947 (Box 36)
  - Science and Metaphysics, McKeon, 1946 (Box 36)
  - Berkeley and Hume, Hortshorne, 1947 (Box 36)
  - Readings in 17th century Philosophy, 1948 (Box 36)
  - Work on Sefer Baal Shem Tov, undated (Box 36)
  - German Existentialism: Bergstraesser, essay: "On Existential Communication", undated (Box 36)
  - Bergstraesser: Fichte, Schelling, Hegel, essay: "God in Hegel & SK", undated (Box 36)
  - Aesthetics and Criticism, McKeon, Chicago, 1950 (Box 36)
  - Documents of Jewish Theology, 1948-1950, undated (Box 36)
  - University of Chicago, undated (Box 36)
  - Santayana: Vivas, undated (Box 36)
  - Problems of Medieval Philosophy, undated (Box 36)
  - Martin Buber: Articles and Essays, undated (Box 36)
  - Cohen, Hermann, 1952, undated (Box 36)
  - Nietzche: Thesis Material, undated (Box 36)
  - Thetis Material: PhD, Metaphysics and Method in Novel, undated (Box 36)
  - Salomon, Albert, undated (Box 36)
  - Glatzer, Nahum, 1961-1965, undated (Box 36)
  - "Nature of Paradox in Kierkegaard and Nietzsche," dissertation, 1948 (Box 36)
  - Processing notes (Box 37)
  - Miscellaneous, 1965-1982 (Box 37)
  - "Fatal Attractions," novella, 1984 (Box 37)
  - Gifts to Yale University Library, Judaica and Hebraica Collection, 1983-1993 (Box 37)
  - Ex Libris Advertising, 1980-1983 (Box 37)
  - Unpublished interview with Robert Motherwell, 1969 (Box 37)
  - Ron Padgett, 1965, undated (Box 37)
  - Ex Libris: Marcel Jean, 1977-1978 (Box 37)
  - Abrahams, Edward, correspondence, 1978-1986 (Box 37)
  - Jean, Marcel, Surrealist Anthology, 1968-1978 (Box 37)
  - Johns, Jasper, 1968-1969 (Box 37)
  - Bann, Stephen, 1968, undated (Box 37)
  - Seuphor, Michel: correspondence, 1969-1983 (Box 37)
  - Brach, Paul, 1967 (Box 37)
  - Baljeu, Joost: correspondence DTCA, 1969 (Box 37)
  - Feldman, Irving, correspondence, 1977 (Box 37)
  - Amichai, Yehuda, undated (Box 37)
  - Levy, Julien, 1976-1977 (Box 37)
  - Brodsky, Joseph, 1973 (Box 37)
  - Ashbery, John, correspondence DTCA, 1967-1968 (Box 37)
  - Salomon, University of Constanz Archives, undated (Box 37)
  - Eliade, Mircea, correspondence, 1964-1985, undated (Box 37)
  - Oz, Amos, correspondence, 1975-1985, undated (Box 37)
  - Flohr, Paul Mendes, 1982-1985, undated (Box 37)
  - Shapiro, David, 1979, undated (Box 37)
  - Markish, Shimon, 1982-1986 (Box 37)
  - Stern, David, undated (Box 37)
  - Bowlt, John, Modern Russian, 1968-1970 (Box 37)
  - McKeon, 1948-1951 (Box 37)
  - Answer to Heschel, 1953 March 5 (Box 37)
  - Tracy, David, correspondence, 1985, undated (Box 37)
  - Mirsky, Mark, 1982-1986, undated (Box 37)
  - Kosinski, Jerzy, 1983, undated (Box 37)
  - Mandelstam, Osip & Nadezhda, 1973 (Box 37)
  - Correspondence: personal, 1986 (Box 37)
  - Awards, 1985-1986, undated (Box 37)
  - Cohen books, 1988 (Box 37)
  - Crossroad/Continuum Publishing Co., 1985 (Box 37)
  - University of Chicago, 1988 (Box 37)
  - Hebrew Correspondence & Essays, undated (Box 37)
  - Cohen: Selected Essays 1959-1983, Godine, 1984 (Box 37)
  - Hero/Simon reviews, undated (Box 37)
  - Hebrew/Yale, 1982-1990 (Box 37)
  - Godine: general publishing correspondence, 1984-1986 (Box 37)
  - Godine Artists and Enemies, 1987 (Box 37)
  - Wallace & Sheils: Literary Agent, 1981-2001 (Box 37)
  - Carcanet, 1985-1986 (Box 37)
  - German Translation: In the Days of Simon Stern. Christa Sartorius. Insel/Suhrkamp Verlag, 1979-1981 (Box 37)
  - German publisher correspondence, 1981 (Box 37)
  - Opera outline, 1984 (Box 37)
  - Rosen, Jerome, Opera Amerika, 1983-1985 (Box 37)
  - Hartman, Geoffrey, Yale University Judaic Studies Development, 1981-1987 (Box 37)
  - The Pastor, draft of play, undated (Box 37)
  - Motherwell, Robert and Helen, 1967-1986 (Box 37)
  - Gidal, Nachum T, 1985 (Box 37)
  - Borchardt, Georges, correspondence, 1963-1962 (Box 37)
  - Heer, F., 1963, 1989 (Box 37)
  - Halakhic Man, Columbia University seminar on Studies in Religion, unpublished, 1986 February 3 (Box 37)
  - Trust Agreement & Will: correspondence with Gould, Bank, Sussmann (Box 37)
  - Diane Cole profiles Arthur A. Cohen, Present Tense, 1981 (Box 37)
  - Audiovisual Material
    Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Milton Steinberg, "New Currents in Religious Thought", circa 1950 (1 of 6), 1997 January; 1; 01:07:16; Clicks and pops can be heard on the tape. There are frequent skips in the program. Sounds like a transfer of a grooved disc. (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091247297)
      American Jewish Historical Society
    - Milton Steinberg, "New Currents in Religious Thought", circa 1950 (2 of 6), 1997 January; 1; 00:46:48; Clicks and pops can be heard on the tape. An echo can be heard during the program. (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091247305)
    - Milton Steinberg, "New Currents in Religious Thought", circa 1950 (3 of 6), 1997 January; 1; Clicks and pops can be heard on the tape. An echo can be heard on the tape. Sounds like a transfer of a grooved disc. There are frequent skips in the program. (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091247313)
    - Milton Steinberg, "New Currents in Religious Thought", circa 1950 (4 of 6), 1997 January; 1; 00:50:50; Clicks and pops are heard on the tape. An echo can be heard at times on the tape. (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091247321)
    - Milton Steinberg, "New Currents in Religious Thought", circa 1950 (5 of 6), 1997 January; 1; 01:08:43; Clicks and pops can be heard on the tape. An echo can be heard on the tape. Sounds like the program was transferred from a grooved disc. There are frequent skips in the program. (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091247339)
    - Milton Steinberg, "New Currents in Religious Thought", circa 1950 (6 of 6), 1997 January; 1; 01:06:52; Clicks and pops can be heard on the tape. An echo can be heard on the tape. There are frequent skips in the program. Sounds like the program was transferred from a grooved disc. The sound is not clear at the beginning of the tape. (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091247347)
    - Arthur A. Cohen, Brown University Religious Studies Seminar, "History of Judaism in Modern Times" (1972-1973) and Hebrew Union College Seminar, NY (1977)
      - R-3, Franz Ros., Brown University (1 of 2), 1973; 1; 01:14:59 (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091247354)
      - R3-3, Frosenzweig, Brown University (2 of 2), 1973; 1; 00:36:15 (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091247362)
      - Metaethics, "Star", Book 1, 1977 February 23; 1; 01:13:24 (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091247370)
      - Book One, Part 2, "Creation Star", 1977 March 4; 1; 00:00:32; The program was recorded at a very low level. (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091247396)
      - Last session on FR's "Creation Star of Redemption", 1977 March 11; 1; 01:22:33 (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091247388)
      - Revelation with passage from SK "Concept of Dread", March 16; 1; 01:10:58 (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091247404)
      - Metalogos, Negative Cosmology, 1977 February 16; 1; 01:06:09 (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091247412)
      - F. Rosenzweig, Metaphysis, 1977 February 11; 1; 01:19:37 (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091247420)
      - Seminar, "Star Introduction on the Possibility of the All" / "Mystic Epistomology" / "Star of Redemption", 1977 February 9; 1; 01:26:12 (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091247438)
      - Metaphor / Language / Consciousness, 1977 February 18; 1; 01:15:42; Static can be heard on the tape. (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091247446)
      - Revelation, March 18; 1; 00:59:11 (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091247453)
      - FR "Creation", 2nd session, 1977 March 9; 1; 00:01:24 (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091247461)
    - "Arthur A. Cohen and Mordecai M. Kaplan interviews for If Not Now, When? " (10 cassettes), 1971 (Box 38)
      - 1st Session, 1971 September 10; 1; 01:24:31; High background noise can be heard on the tape. Static can be heard. Audio is not clear in parts. (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091247511)
      - 2nd Session, 1971 September 14; 1; 01:26:36; Sound on the tape is not always clear. (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091247529)
      - 3rd Session (1 of 2), 1971 September 17; 1; 00:32:12; A high amount of hiss can be heard on the tape. (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091247537)
      - 3rd Session (2 of 2), 1971 September 17; 1 (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091247552)
      - 4th Session, 1971 September 24; 1; 01:04:55; Audio is not clear at times. (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091247545)
      - 5th Session, September 25; 1; 01:18:29 (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091247560)
      - 6th Session / 7th Session (beginning), 1971 October 1; 1; 01:29:17; A high amount of background noise can be heard on the tape. (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091247578)
      - 7th Session (end) / 7th Session, 1971 October 5; 1; 00:58:27 (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091247586)
      - 8th Session (end) / 9th Session (beginning), 1971 October 5, 7; 1; 00:38:06 (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091247594)
      - 9th Session (end), 1971 October 7; 1; 00:21:43; Audio on the tape is not always clear. (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091247602)
    - Amos Oz in a dialogue with Arthur A. Cohen, 1983 November 14; 1; 01:27:16; Static and distortion can be heard throughout the first 45 minutes of the tape. (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091247503)
    - "God and the Jews After Auschwitz", 1981 January 10; 1; 01:14:23; The program is distorted at times. A high amount of buzz can be heard on the tape. (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091247495)
    - Long Island Council of Jewish Women: Arthur A. Cohen, Neal Kozodoy, Cynthia Ozick, 1973 November 27; 1; 01:20:33; The program was recorded at a very low level at times. The sound is not always clear on the tape. (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091247487)
    - Arthur A. Cohen interviewed by Rena Blumberg, Cleveland Radio, 1980 April 18; 1; 00:28:06 (Box 38, Item barcode 39002091247479)
    - "Open End, David Susskind, 1960, What is UnAmerican, Arthur A. Cohen, Frank Donner, Fulton Lewis III, M. Stanton Evans, Godfrey Schmidt, John H. Faulk" (4 vinyl records) (Box 38)
    - "Luncheon Meeting -- Adult Jewish Education, Waldorf-Astoria Hotel, N.Y.C." (audiotape reel), 1966 March 13; 1 (Box 46, Item barcode 39002091247271)
    - "Home Show 4/9/59, Arthur Cohen, Pres, Meridian Books, 12 East 22 St." (audiotape reel), 1959; 1 (Box 46, Item barcode 39002091247289)
  - Letters to Elaine Lustig Cohen regarding Arthur A. Cohen's death, 1986 (Box 39)
  - Photographs of Arthur A. Cohen, Elaine Lustig Cohen, and others, 1930s-1980s; 5 (Box 40)
  - Ephemera relating to Noonday Press and Meridian Books, 1954-1963 (Box 40)
  - Photographs "Northern Italy" and portrait of Cohen, 1949 Summer and 1955 (Box 41)
  - The Meridian, Volume 1, Number 1, 1957 Spring (Box 41)
- December 2010 Acquisition, 1940s-1980s; 1.88; (4 boxes)
  - Arthur A. Cohen correspondence, 1940s; 2 (Box 42)
  - Arthur A. Cohen play, circa 1968 (Box 42)
  - Arthur A. Cohen correspondence, 1938-1950; 2 (Box 42)
  - Bess Junger Cohen - I. M. [Isidore Meyer] Cohen (Box 42)
  - Bibliographic log, 1979 (Box 42)
  - Cohen, I. M. [Isidore Meyer], correspondence, 1966 (Box 42)
  - Cohen, I. M. [Isidore Meyer], correspondence, 1950s-1960s (Box 42)
  - Correspondence, parents, 1940s-1960s (Box 42)
  - Correspondence, special, 1940s-1960s (Box 42)
  - Drafts (Box 42)
  - Graphic Design Coming of Age, 1983 (Box 42)
  - The Hebrew Bible in Christian, Jewish and Muslim Art, 1963 (Box 42)
  - Cohen, I. M. [Isidore Meyer] (Box 42)
  - International Design Conference Aspen, 1962 (Box 42)
  - Journal, 1967 (Box 42)
  - Journal, "3/8/77 New York, 4/2/82 Galilea Mallerga", 1977 March 8; 1982 April 2 (Box 42)
  - Journal, "12/5/82 Galilea", circa 1982 (Box 42)
  - Untitled, 1985 June 27-28 (Box 42)
  - The Last Soliloquuy (Box 42)
  - Living Legacy: Essays on Hugo Han, ed. Bernhard N. Cohn, 1963 (Box 42)
  - Draft of play [Mr. Rex's Career, the Adam Man] (Box 43)
  - Meridian (Box 42)
  - The Meridian, 1957-1959 (Box 42)
  - Meridian Books Paperback Publishing (Box 42)
  - Miscellaneous, 1950s-1970s (Box 42)
  - The Negative Way: A Collaboration, Arthur A. Cohen, circa 1964 (Box 45 Oversize)
    Ten lithographs by Paul Brach, printed at Tamarind Workshop
  - Notes on projects in progress, 1964 April 31; 1979 (Box 43)
  - Novella in progress (Box 43)
  - On the Marionette Theater of Heinrich von Kleist, Arthur A. Cohen, 1988 (Box 45 Oversize)
    A fragment from an edition of forty-five, printed by Kaldewey Press, Poestenkill, NY. Woodblock illustrations by Elaine Lustig Cohen
  - Photographs and miscellaneous (Box 43)
  - Photograph, "Young Americans in the News", 1944 January 30 (Box 43)
  - Plays in progress (Box 43)
  - Scimons, 1957-1960 (Box 43)
  - "Shocken Books" catalog, The Enchanted Princess, misc. manuscript., 1954-1955 (Box 43)
  - Steinberg - Milton, correspondence, 1940s (Box 43)
  - Writings and correspondence (Box 43)
  - Writing - miscellaneous (Box 43)
  - United States Dressage Federation (Box 43)
  - 1981 "Avant Garde in Present" red (Box 43)
  - Audiovisual material
    Box 44 contains audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Arthur Cohen, "Eternal Light" / "Simon Stern", NBC, 1973 October 7; 1; 00:25:15; A high amount of background noise can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 44, Item barcode 39002091247255)
    - Cohen / G. Weigel, NRC, "Catholic Hour", 1960 May 22; 1; 00:29:33; Static can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. An audible echo can be heard on the tape as well. (Box 44, Item barcode 39002091247263)
    - Compact discs - Motherwell / Cohen, Provincetown (Box 44)
      Contains five writeable compact discs, with dates ranging from August 11 to August 18, 1969